Freddie Zhang

260 Summit Blvd. Apt 8302., Broomfield, CO, 80021 | 720-297-9208 | yozh2004@colorado.edu

OBJECTIVE

Innovative and passionate student with rich experience in data science pursuing a master's degree in business analytics at Leeds School of Business to begin a career as a statistics analyst, with a combination of my undergraduate majors of Economics and Computer Science.

EDUCATION

University of Colorado Boulder Boulder, Colorado

M. S. Business Analytics 8/2019

Major GPA: 3.850

B. A. Computer Science

B. A. Economics 5/2018

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Computer Skills

C++, Python, MATLAB, Scala, Stata, JavaScript, Tableau, IntelliJ IDEA, SQL, R, Swift 3, Mathematica, VBA, Microsoft Excel, Word, PowerPoint

Language Skills

English, Mandarin

EXPERIENCE

Climate Change Analysis Boulder, Colorado Team Member 3/2017-5/2017

- A data mining project examines the trend of climate change since 1750
- Cleaned and visualized the data set through Matlab, Python, and R
- Demonstrated the relationship between climate change and global warming in different area and country
- Presented final presentation to the class and received an A

A Buddy in the Sky Project

Boulder, Colorado Team Leader 2/2017-5/2017

- A software design project that designing an iOS-based game
- The project followed iterative methodology and is a long-term project that planned in advance
- The game is based on SpriteKit as physical engine and used Swift 3 in Xcode as the major tool
- Worked as team leader and programmed the entire game

Data Analyst Internship

Everlight Electronics Co., Ltd

Taiwan, China 6/2017-8/2017

- Worked as a team member at the operation department
- Assisted in analyzing sales data to maintain the balance of sell-in and sell-through
- Participated in further research in some projects, including dealing with data and modeling
- Communicated with customers including Everstar Electronics Co., Ltd

PROFESSIONAL MEMBERSHIPS

Boulder Freeride, University of Colorado Boulder

10/2014 - Present